{
    "id": "bdc8b5839dd54c589b070e4377c8cf0c",
    "title": "Tenses Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "He crashed his car shortly after he ………………………. it.",
            "description": "The past perfect is used for the earlier of the two past actions. ",
            "answers": [
                "bought",
                "had bought",
                "has bought"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I …………………….. my work before I went out to play.",
            "description": "The simple past is also possible here, but the past perfect is considered more approrpriate. ",
            "answers": [
                "finished",
                "had finished",
                "have finished"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "He ……………………… ill for about a month before he died.",
            "description": "The past perfect is used for an action or situation that started at some point in the past and continued up to another point. ",
            "answers": [
                "was",
                "has been",
                "had been"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "The show ………………………… before we reached the venue.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "has begun",
                "had begun",
                "began"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "No one took care of the children after their parents …………………………",
            "description": "The simple past is also possible here but the past perfect is more appropriate. ",
            "answers": [
                "died",
                "have died",
                "had died"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "We ………………………….. here since",
            "description": "The present perfect continuous is used to talk about an action or situation that started in the past and has continued up to the present. ",
            "answers": [
                "are living",
                "were living",
                "have been living",
                "had been living"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "He …………………………. here for 2 hours.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "is waiting",
                "was waiting",
                "has been waiting"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "I ……………………… them for a long time.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "am not meeting",
                "have not met",
                "do not meet"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Although the driver was badly hurt, he could explain what ……………………….",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "happened",
                "have happened",
                "had happened"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "Neither of the boys ………………………….. arrived.",
            "description": "Use a singular verb after neither.",
            "answers": [
                "has",
                "have"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "One of the students ………………………… missing.",
            "description": "Use a singular verb after one of.",
            "answers": [
                "are gone",
                "have gone",
                "has gone"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "How they ................................. is a mystery.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "escape",
                "have escaped",
                "escaped"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        }
    ]
}